Welcome back to a push in under three
minutes. No time for intros. Let's get
into it. So, reconstruction was supposed
to fix the South and bring equality for
all African-Americans, but instead it
completely failed. At first, things
looked promising. Black men gained
citizenship and voting rights. Over
2,000 African-Americans held public
office and federal troops were stationed
in the South to enforce reconstruction
policies. But, white southerners hated
this and they fought back hard. We
already talked about some examples of
this being sharecropping, lynchings, and
organizations like the KKK, but you also
had things like convict leasing, where
black men were arrested for madeup
crimes and forced into unpaid labor.
Then came the Supreme Court, which
basically gave up on protecting black
rights. The slaughterhouse cases in 1873
gutted the 14th Amendment by saying
civil rights were a state issue, not a
federal one. in the US v that they said
that the federal government couldn't
punish white mobs that murdered black
Americans. With no one left to enforce
black rights, white southerners took
control again. And then came the final
nail in the coffin being the compromise
of 1877. Essentially, the 1876
presidential election was a mess. So,
Republicans and Democrats made a
backroom deal. The North would remove
troops from the South, and in return,
they would elect a Republican Rutherford
Be Hayes as president. But this would
mean reconstruction would end and the
South could do whatever it wanted. So
that's exactly what happened. Black
rights were crushed for nearly a
century. Jim Crow laws, segregation, and
voter suppression took over.
Reconstruction was the US's first
attempt at civil rights, and it failed
miserably. But the 14th and 15th
Amendments didn't go away. They became
the legal foundation for the civil
rights movement a 100red years later. On
the screen now are some AP style
questions for this topic. Pause
now. I'll put the answers on the screen
now. I will see you in the next one.